Owen Edwards

Web Developer

Profile

Creative web developer with an eye for writing quality code and a passion for creating beautiful, responsive websites.

3+ years of experience with Javascript, React, PHP, and others. Seeking a full time position in a growing company to develop my skills and find new challenges and experiences.

Employment History

Web Developer at Core Creative Limited, Yeovil

December 2021 — Present

Web Developer for a leading South West creative design agency, working with a small team to manage a large number of sites for a variety of global clients.

- Worked closely with designers and clients to deliver high quality websites and email campaigns.
- Responsible for working with global brands to delivery quality and consistent products.
- Maintained a close relationship with clients, ensuring that all accounts were progressing well and that all needs were met.
- Developed front-end elements for many sites, working from provided designs and delivering with accuracy and speed.
- · Working with PHP, Javascript and Wordpress.

Web Developer at AUTP, Nottingham

December 2020 — September 2021

Web developer for the UK charity, the Association of University Teachers of Psychiatry.

- Tasked with updating the general site layout, making key resources and information easier to access.
- Provided a number of reusable templates for event banners and webinar information.
- Overhauled the online event experience by streamlining the process of sending out invites and post event certificates, while being on hand during events to ensure things ran smoothly and that any technical questions were immediately answered.
- Maintained the upcoming and recent event pages, and created advertisements and banner ads for AUTP events as needed.

Shop Assistant at The Locked Horns, Chepstow

January 2014 — January 2016

Served as a friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee in a customer facing role.

 Worked to improve the organisation and record keeping of the stock room.

Details

97 Goldcroft Yeovil, BA214DF +44 7468966914 owenhedwards@gmail.com

Skills

JavaScript (ES6), Typescript, PHP

CSS, SCSS, Styled Components, Bootstrap

React.js, Redux

Node.js, Express

HTML

Wordpress

PostgreSQL

Git, GitHub

Photoshop, Indesign

Links

www.owenedwards.me

Interests

I have a love of classical history and english literature, writing short stories, programming personal projects, creating mods for favourite games, and travelling to interesting places. Managed the front desk and provided recommendations for customers, while maintaining a friendly and professional attitude.

Education

Humanities, Coleg Gwent, Newport

September 2015 — September 2016

English and Classics, University of Nottingham, Nottingham

September 2016 — January 2019

★ Recent Projects

Student Psychiatry, www.studentpsychiatry.co.uk

February 2021 — March 2021

A full-stack web app aimed at student psychiatrists, and psychiatry event organizers.

React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express, Express-Session, Styled Components.

- Secure login managed with express-session that requires users to register with a valid UK university email addresses. This was a feature requested by the university medical societies I consulted to help keep online event links from leaking to the public.
- Moderation features allowing approved event organizers to add their own events to the calendar. Event information is stored on a PostgreSQL database, using the Sequelize ORM.

NPC Generator, www.communitychargen.co.uk

December 2020 — January 2021

A fun personal project that not only provides easily accessed random characters for tabletop games, but also allows users to upload their own character ideas to the generator.

React.js, Redux, Node.js, Express, Cloudinary, Styled Components.

- Full-stack web app. Front end created with React, back end created with Node.js and Express.
- Quickly generate characters for tabletop games while also allowing users to register and add their own data for others to discover.
- Character text data is stored on a PostgreSQL database using KNEX.js, while images are stored on Cloudinary. Image moderation is handled through the Cloudinary interface, using the API to update moderation status on the server and database.

Courses

Modern JavaScript From The Beginning, Udemy

April 2019 — October 2019

The Complete Web Developer Bootcamp, Udemy

October 2020 — March 2020